Can the most famous film star in the world fall for the man on the street?
Notting Hill is a romance, comedy film directed by Roger Michell.
London bookstore owner William Thacker's quiet life turns upside down when a chance encounter with famous
actress Anna Scott sparks an unlikely romance challenged by their vastly different worlds.
Anna Scott, played by Julia Roberts.
William Thacker, played by Hugh Grant.
Bella, played by Gina McKee.
Max, played by Tim McInnerny.
Spike, played by Rhys Ifans.
Honey, played by Emma Chambers.
Notting Hill is a 1999 romantic comedy film directed by Roger Michell,
written by Richard Curtis, and produced by Duncan Kenworthy.
It stars Julia Roberts and Hugh Grant, with Rhys Ifans, Emma Chambers, Tim
McInnerny, Gina McKee, and Hugh Bonneville in supporting roles.
The story is of a romance between a British bookshop keeper (Grant) and a famous American actress
(Roberts) who happens to walk into his shop in London's Notting Hill district.
Released on 21 May 1999, Notting Hill was well received by critics and was the
highest-grossing British film of all time upon release, which has since been eclipsed.
At the 57th Golden Globe Awards, the film received three nominations – Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy, Best
Actress – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy (Roberts) and Best Actor – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy (Grant).
It also earned two BAFTA nominations, and won a British
Comedy Award and a Brit Award for its soundtrack.
The film explores themes of new love, london, england,
bookshop, roommates, press conference.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.